<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Scripts</title>
    <link>http://harish678.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Scripts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://harish678.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iterators and Generators</title>
      <link>http://harish678.github.io/posts/iteratorgenerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://harish678.github.io/posts/iteratorgenerator/</guid>
      <description>Iterator Iterator is an object that can loop over iterable objects. We can use Iterator in for loops. A list is a well known Iterator.
Implementaion An object can be a Iterator, if we implement two methods:
 __iter__ - returns the object itself. __next__ - returns the next values and raises StopIteration exception when all objects are looped.   Generator Generator functions allow you to declare a function that behaves like an iterator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decorators</title>
      <link>http://harish678.github.io/posts/decorators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://harish678.github.io/posts/decorators/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Before looking into Decorators, we need to know key points about Functions in Python.
 Functions are Objects. Means they can be referenced, passed as an argument, can be returned as well.  Decorators dynamically alter the functionality of a function, method, or class without having to directly use subclasses or change the source code of the function being decorated Implementaion Function as a Decorator Boilerplate Code:
import functools def decorator(func): @functools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Manager</title>
      <link>http://harish678.github.io/posts/contextmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://harish678.github.io/posts/contextmanager/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Context managers allow you to allocate and release resources precisely when you want to. The most widely used example of context managers is the with statement.
Suppose you have two related operations which you’d like to execute as a pair, with a block of code in between. Context managers allow you to do specifically that.
Implementaion In the below example we will implement a program to open the file and read its contents using two methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
